KIMBERLY OWENS

Phone: 303.915.0366 | | Email: <u>kimberly.j.owens@gmail.com</u> | | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kimberly-owens27 | | GitHub: https://github.com/kimberlyj227 | | Portfolio: https://kimberlyj227.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Psychology and life-long dedication to learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known for having a positive attitude and a calm, focused demeanor under pressure.

Key Strengths

Project Management · Process Improvement · Data Analysis · Organization · Teamwork and Collaboration · Grasps new concepts quickly

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React

Other: MySQL, Sequelize, Mongo, Mongoose, Node.js, jQuery, Microsoft Office, Adobe Suite, Git collaboration

Projects

Worthy Origin | GitHub Repository: https://github.com/kimberlyj227/Worthy-Origin | Deployed Project: https://worthyorigin.herokuapp.com/

- An app that allows the user to view carbon footprint of certain food items
- I contributed to the design of the site, coding the facts page, and the backend routes to the database.
- Technologies used: Node.js, React.js, JavaScript, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose

Pantheos | GitHub Repository: https://github.com/kimberlyj227/Pantheos |

Deployed Project: https://pantheos-education.herokuapp.com/

- The student information tracker for teachers to streamline communication and reports of students records.
- I mainly developed front-end using handlebars. I also helped debug, wrote some of the backend routes and served as project manager.
- Technologies used: Node.js, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Express, Lodash, jQuery, mySQL2, and Sequelize

Lyric Cloud | GitHub Repository: https://github.com/kimberlyj227/lyric-map/tree/gh-pages |

Deployed Project: https://kimberlyj227.github.io/lyric-map/

- This app allows users to search for a song by artist and song title and creates a word cloud out of the lyrics to the song
- I made this app to work with data visualization libraries and to get more experience with React.
- Technologies used: React, JavaScript, CSS, react-d3-cloud

Professional Experience

Program Director/Head Coach 2019 – 2019

Gymnastics East Bellevue, WA

• Developed clear and executable short-term and long-term training plans for gymnasts under my supervision. Communicated daily with parents and co-coaches on a daily basis.

Program Coordinator 2016 – 2019

Seattle Gymnastics Academy Seattle, WA

Developed clear and executable short-term and long-term training plans for gymnasts under my supervision. Communicated daily with parents and co-coaches on a daily basis.

Key Accomplishments:

- Managed a project to develop new curriculum and coaches training for the program I oversaw
- Developed training using Articulate Storyline software

Assistant Program Director 2011 – 2016

JCC Dallas Dallas, TX

Managed social media and created marketing collateral for the gymnastics program. Managed class schedules. Provided leadership to gymnasts and coaches under my supervision.

Key Accomplishments:

Created and managed a database for the program to keep track of past and present students

Quality Assurance/Document Control 2010 – 2011

Quest Medical Allen, TX

Responsible for auditing about 20 records on a daily basis to ensure FDA and company compliance. Analyzed quality control practices to identify and eliminate documentation processing errors. Assisted in QA/RA audits.

Key Accomplishments:

- After one month as an intern in a temporary role, Quest Medical offered me a permanent position reviewing documents and analyzing data
- Developed metrics to track and analyze various aspects of the quality control process
- Managed a project to reformat Device History Records to improve efficiency and eliminate documentation errors

Education and Certifications

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Denver, Denver, CO

A 13-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, and ReactJS. I earned 240 contact hours and spent about 40+ hours a week coding and working on various projects.

B.A Psychology: Ouachita Baptist University, Arkadelphia, AR